At this point, we are about
ready to use the command line.
Let's talk about a
couple of command line essentials.
First thing to realize is
that Linux is case sensitive.
So if you see lowercase, you type lowercase
because if you type uppercase it won't work.
Also, you should realize that there is
an exception to any generic statement on Linux.
Linux is open source, and because
of the decentralized development of different Linux
components, there are always exceptions to
things that you consider to be true.
Let's use an example of how to
quit an interactive interface. Sometimes you need
control C, sometimes you need Q, sometimes
you need to type quit. It all
depends on the discretion of the
open source developer behind the project.
Now, while you are working with
commands, commands are often used with options.
And these options can
be specified as long options.
And long options start
with double hyphen. So Uname
Help is printing help
for the Uname command.
There's also short options, and short options start
with a single hyphen and they can be
defined. So instead of using LS l r
minus T, you can also type LS lrt.
Linux commands typically
have many options.
If you want to know about these many options, you
use Help on any command to learn how to use it.
Let me
show you.
Let's use the LS command as an example.
If I type ls, then it works. If I
type LS in uppercase, then I'm getting command
not found. But fortunately my shell is friendly enough
to tell me that it knows about
similar commands, which is LS in all lowercase.
Now how
about these options?
LS Help is giving me a list of all of the options
and oh my goodness, that doesn't fit on the screen now does it?
If I scroll up a little bit, I can see all
these options and as you can see, it's an entire Alphabet.
Now if you look at the l
option, there we go. L uses a long
listing format, and it's kind of funny,
L only exists as a short option.
There are also options like
k for kibibytes that exist
as a short option as
well as a long option.
So LS l K will show
you kibibytes for all of the valves,
but you can also use LS
l kibibytes to show the kibibytes value.
For now, I
think that's enough.
Let's explore some more commands
in the next couple of.